it's always fun to have you I'm pumped
up we're my I I met myy like 10 years
ago I went to a show you and you met him
I well yeah I have a picture with him I
was trying to look for it on my
Instagram but I can't find it oh but um
he's a nice guy and it's I say Mory poic
what's the right way poic okay oh I was
saying p i sometimes I say pich I think
you said pich in the pich which is the
right way well ask him I just say I feel
like he's a guy you can ask how do you
say your name that we we should all know
this and I feel like you could just go
with Mory and everybody knows who it is
there's no other Mor Mor Tuesdays with t
right Tuesdays with Mor yeah I I read
that book and like got something from it
same samies I was like oh I'm going to
start like forgiving everyone yeah when
I was in physical therapy school like we
had to learn about ALS and I like
couldn't come I couldn't study and focus
on it so I just like I'll read Tuesdays
with Mor because he had ALS and I just
yeah I failed because like you had to
like know you to like know I mean it's a
graduate program and I was like I'm just
going to read this
novel
[Music]
poic is in the studio everyone I told
you he was going to drop by it was going
to happen quick we're Ready's up brother
how you doing that's Chris this is
Andrew
hi nice to meet you good to see you oh
it's um so many people uh so many I mean
this s everybody everyone's so excited
about you when I talk about you it's
people glow they they have a story they
have a relationship with you um and I
learned last night from doing some
research that you're you were the a
current affair guy of course yeah I mean
of course but I was a child when that
show was on so I didn't like you you
actually watched it yes my mom watched
it and I loved it it it gave me an
appreciation for
really journalism kach yes kach I
remember all of it but I forgot that
that was you and then you became myy
Povich just making the connection I
loved that show well that that show
first of all the kach you know the the
the sound it came
from we we always said when we started
the show we wanted to have something
like the 60 Minutes clock so that if you
heard it oh it's on you know and you
would watch so they put a the oldtime
elementary school construction paper
Cutters the sound of a construction
paper cutter put with the swish of a
golf club put through a synthesizer and
that was named after my wife the
kach it's so good us those are all such
satisfying sounds layered on top of each
other know it makes sense why it works
it was like in the day this is like the
mid this is like 86 so it was the the
first days of synthesiz say and so
that's that's what they use oh and it
worked I remember it it's still yeah
that was always something my mom had on
but now myy you you've taken your mom
still has my show on now yeah now
exactly oh my gosh everyone has your sh
I mean in this room they've we know up
both my producer and Chris Stephano have
you been do a live taping I have not but
I'm going tomorrow we you all been but
they've been liveing yeah I was there 10
years ago it was awesome I was trying to
look for I got a picture with you too
crazy yeah it's really this is the
tourist thing to do when you come to New
York City why aren't you going to a the
live taping of my show is as good ENT
entertainment as you would ever want my
live audience makes the show I mean it's
the heart of the show cuz they go crazy
yeah and they all think they know who
the father is when we in my episode when
we found out it was the father we went
out of our minds it was like the
touchdown like it was like and because
before we were like there's no way he's
the father and then when he was we like
well Chris you were saying in line there
was talking in line there were
people of in the episode that I was at
the family of one of the the guy on the
show and they were like he's I know he's
the father I know he's the father and
then people were like you know nobody
knows anything I was with my friends are
like no he's not no he's not we have no
we have no frame of reference then when
he was like we were just like wow and
then like I told you I know Vivid
memories these people are Conjuring just
from being at your show 10 years ago it
truly sounds like such a great life
experience to have I uh I heard a story
of an NFL quarterback this is many years
ago said that the the players would be
in the locker room and they would not go
out to practice until they found out who
the was losing Shaquille O'Neal
watches my show every single day wow and
Shaq said and what he does is he calls
up all his friends and they bet on who
the father is great I love it so fun and
Noah I wanted to give you a second to
tell myy what you he means to you
because you went to a taping yeah so I I
took a TV production class in high
school this is like 15 years years ago
and I went to a live taping of your show
and that's when I knew that I had to
work in production I was watching your
stage manager and I was just like
mesmerized like what is that job I want
to do something like that really yeah
and that's when you got the the itch
yeah and that and then from then on I
knew that I so you've been in production
ever since yeah Isn't that cool you
produce this show yes yeah how's it
going amazing it's the best my
life it's so fun do how do you how do
you I'm guessing people are having fun
working on your show how have you well
it's it's the most amazing part about
that is that my producers my associate
producers my
cameramen uh have been there for 15 20
years uh they people like the atmosphere
the the way we work the work environment
uh I have I I started the first talk
show I did was for Paramount and that
was like 28 years ago and uh I still
have five people
throughout my staff who who've been with
me 28 years wow I mean I I mean I've got
impressive as they say you sent my kids
through school now they've got kids I
mean now those kids are ready to go to
school I mean and it's but it starts at
the top I mean people who enjoy it
starts with you and that just is a
credit to you but attct I always look
it's this business I is is I mean I've
seen so much in the television radio
business in my life life that uh uh it's
easy to pick out the fools and so uh the
you know the the a-holes uh show
themselves very early and so therefore
uh you know exactly what to guard
against and so that's that's how I do
and as far as like the suits you know
the executives yeah there's nothing
better to keep distance between you and
the suits than a good rating if you get
a good rating they don't care about you
yeah yeah you'll never hear from them
you'll never get a note you they'll
they're they're your best
friend the second but the second the
race moment there's a dip the moment
there's a dip well we think that you
ought to do this really where the hell
have you been yes oh yeah who am I
speaking to even um I I wanted to ask
you about the Daily Grind of doing a
show so I mean how many episodes are we
talking and 4,000 how many have you done
oh gosh it's between three and 4,000
yeah insane um so how many do you tape a
week we tape five a week uh I tape
usually we tape in Stanford Stanford
Connecticut and we tape three on
Thursdays and two on
Fridays uh we work about I don't know 27
weeks a year do I don't know 30 or 40
shows what is it do you ever reach a
point where you're like okay again like
how do you muster the because you never
seem bored of it how do you must because
because I believe even though for
instance between the lie detector themes
and the DNA themes that's those are our
two signature themes yeah but since I
came out of news many for many many
years I've always believed in
storytelling and I just want to find
even with those two themes all the time
unique qualities of every single story
and so I believe
each person each personality has a
unique quality about them either good or
bad that I can bring out and if I
continue to do that I won't get bored
and so that's you know that's my Mantra
that's really cool and you can tell that
that's why we love the show Bring Out
characters and the other thing is and
I've always said this about talk shows
uh and I learned this a long time ago
when I first started it's like being in
a in a campaign to be elected you have
to knock on somebody's door they have to
open the door door they have to welcome
you in they have to feel so comfortable
with you that they'll sit you at the
table or sit you on the couch and you
have to become a member of that family
and if you that if you can do that then
you got a chance of being success
successful that's that's the way I've
looked at it all my life and I've looked
on it as being an advocate for the
audience all that's why for instance I
don't know I've never known the result
of any DNA test or lie detector test
before before I opened up the envelope
cuzz you're an advocate for the audience
you you're representing their experience
right and I don't want to know anything
more than they do if I because if I did
then I'd skew the questions in a certain
way that's fascinating because I've
hosted two shows two talk shows that
didn't last past two seasons and that I
did feel that there the audience just
didn't get to know me or didn't trust me
and there was some there was some
element of that or wasn't given a chance
to whatever it was but you're really
tapping into something is as a host
trying to approach the job like you're
their Advocate no question it's a it's a
really cool approach and it's Mak sense
why it's working and yet you can bring
out your own vulnerabilities yes I mean
you you bring out your own experiences I
mean for instance I mean I can't tell
you how many times I I've told various
fathers for instance who are raising a
child that is not theirs and whether
they will continue to raise that child I
keep saying look my wife and I have a
child in our family and I I'm not the
birth father of that child and he is as
close to me as my birth children there's
no difference and you so you have to be
able to unload yourself yes to the
guests and the viewers that is extremely
uh compassionate and like and and makes
them that's great that you share that
experience and I and another thing is
that look there is nothing in my life
that comes close to the experiences that
my guests go through I I've never lived
those
experiences but there's some connective
human instinct that they feel safe in my
company or on my show they don't I feel
safe right now I feel completely safe
right now you that air of like a
therapist like I don't feel but I'm not
a therapist I mean no but you're
therapeutic you could just that voice I
don't know what it is I just feel so
good right now you you know how much
whiskey and cigarettes that's what I
like you sound just like my stepmom
great you're you're drunk for sure but I
but I still like man I'm just feel good
my blood pressure is low right now
really how can dude I I just just I have
a v I'm not sweating my heart's not palp
I don't feel like I'm going to pass out
I just feel calm I'm going to get
somebody pregnant tonight just going to
do it I'm coming on your
show cool that's the only way I can get
yeah all right great see you in about
six
[Laughter]
[Music]
months
I